<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Jack Pearson</title>
    <link>https://pearson.onl/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Jack Pearson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pearson.onl/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Noisemaker</title>
      <link>https://pearson.onl/projects/noisemaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pearson.onl/projects/noisemaker/</guid>
      <description>Some waveforms that can be formed with frequency modulation
 Noisemaker is a basic music synthesizing library written in C++. Basically, it provides several basic modules that can control each other&amp;rsquo;s input, add and multiply outputs, and perform other basic functions. The user connects several of these modules together, then chooses an output module to be written to a wav file. The names of the two synthesis techniques this enables are &amp;ldquo;additive&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;frequency modulation&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programmable Music Box</title>
      <link>https://pearson.onl/projects/music-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pearson.onl/projects/music-box/</guid>
      <description>The programmable music box is a project I wrote software for at the Dos Pueblos Engineering academy in my senior year of high school with one other student.
A bare music box
 Normal music boxes are built so that each columns of pins can only play one note. This is because the tines that are plucked by each column have a fixed length.
The programmable music box allows users to create their own tune on a music box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Playing Guitar</title>
      <link>https://pearson.onl/projects/guitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pearson.onl/projects/guitar/</guid>
      <description>The Self-Playing Guitar, or sometimes the Air Guitar, is a project I programmed and partially built with two other students at the Dos Pueblos Engineering Academy in my senior year of high school.
A guitarist performing a hammer-on
 The project is actually a lot more than just a guitar; it has a carriage of pneumatic pistons that act as the &amp;ldquo;fingers&amp;rdquo; that play the guitar, which use a technique called a hammer-on (when a player slams their finger down on the string hard enough that they don&amp;rsquo;t have to strum).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>